Register to The Charles Ives Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, Series III; 13 boxes
  - Correspondence - Institutional, III.B
    - Works Progress Administration
      - (Crandell, George), 1939 Jun 21; typed letter signed with Charles Ives memo (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Writers' Board (Fadiman, Clifton), 1946 May 31; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Who's Who in the World of Music (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - (Koswick, A., Bordsall Publishers, Inc.), 1936 Aug 8; typed letter signed with Charles Ives memo (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - (Donahue, M.), 1936 Jul 21; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - (A.N. Marquis Company), 1932 Jul 1; envelope (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - secretary to Charles Ives, 1942 Apr 13; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - data for article, enc (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - (A.N. Marquis), 1945 Sep 11; envelope with Charles Ives memo (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives to above, 1945 Aug 30; cancelled check (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Who's Who in the World of Music, printed announcement of 24th volume (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - (Walker, C.L.), 1945-1946; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Who's Important in Music
      - (Kaye, S.A.), 1945 Mar 5, Mar 26, 1945 May 14; 3 typed letters signed (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - printed forms, no date; 2 enc with Charles Ives memo (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - (Kaye), 1946 Oct 7; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives to above, no date; draft (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - (Kaye), 1946 Oct 7; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives to above, no date; 2 drafts (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - International Who's Who
      - (?Ampson, Gustaf), 1946 Oct 2; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, no date; draft (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - incomplete, typed list (copy) (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Who's Who in the East (Laskin, Thomas), 1942 Dec 23, 1943 May 20; 2 typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Yale (Box 36, Folder 5)
      X.D
    - Yale Alumni Association (Box 36, Folder 5)
      See also III.B/36/8/Yale Class of 1898
    - The Yale Alumni Weekly (from scrapbook), 1923 Jun 15; printed excerpt (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - (Simmons, Frank H.), 1927 Mar 3; typed postcard signed with Charles Ives memo (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - The Yale Alumni Weekly (from scrapbook), 1931 May 29; printed excerpt (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - (from scrapbook) re above, no date; autograph memo (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - (Simmons), 1935 Jun 1; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - brochure, enc (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - (Bradley, Janet), 1942 Feb 16; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - 1942 Mar, bulletin (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - (Phillips, Marion L.), 1945 May 18; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Yale Club
      - Charles Ives, 1916 Dec 7; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - re American Ambulance Field Service, 1917 May 19; flyer (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Charles Ives to Buckner, Mortimer, 1917 May 24; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Yale Ambulance Fund of Yale Club (Buckner), 1917 May 24; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Charles Ives, 1917 May 28; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - attached to above re insurance, no date; typed memo (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - (Adee, George T.), 1935 Sep 28; typed letter signed (copy) with Charles Ives memo (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Yale University (Box 36, Folder 7)
      See also III.A/29/1/Donovan
      - (Day, George P.), 1941 Mar 11; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Guggenheim re Kirkpatrick, R., 1940 Nov 2; enc typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Charles Ives to above, no date; draft (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Day), 1941 Jun 19, 1942 May 6, Jun 24, 1942 Dec 19; 4 typed letters signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Grumman, Ellsworth), 1943 Feb 1; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Day), 1944 Jul 20, 1945 Jun 18; 2 typed letters signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Grumman), 1945 Jun 22; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Simonds, Bruce), 1947 May 10; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Grumman), 1947 Jun 2, 1951 Feb 22; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Charles Ives to above, no date; draft (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Grumman), 1949 Jun 9; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Grumman) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1951 Mar 5; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Donovan) to Van Santvoord, George, 1953 Feb 4; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Van Santvoord to above, 1953 Feb 6; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Donovan) to Charles Ives, 1953 Mar 24; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Holden, Reuben) to [Noss], Luther, 1953 Nov 18; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to Holden, 1953 Nov 25; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Holden) to Charles Ives, 1954 Feb 15; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to Hblden, 1954 Mar 4; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - (Holden) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1954 Mar 11, Jun 9; 2 typed letters signed (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - degree citation, enc (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Yale University Library (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Keogh, Andrew) (acknowledgements for gifts of Music), 1920 Jun 29; 2 typed letters signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Babb, James T.), 1943 Dec 17; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Charles Ives, no date; draft memo (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Friends of Music at Yale (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Barnes, Courtlandt D.), 1956 Jun 20; typed letter signed (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Yale Music Library
      See also X.D
      - (Shepard, Brooks) to John Kirkpatrick, 1953 Mar 2; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Kirkpatrick, John) to above, 1953 Mar 3; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to John Kirkpatrick, 1953 Mar 9; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1954 Nov 23; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to John Kirkpatrick, 1954 Nov 24; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1954 Dec 3; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to above, 1954 Dec 12, no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Donovan) to Cowell, 1954 Dec 14; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1954 Dec 15, 1955 Jan 5; 2 typed letters signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, no date; draft (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1955 Jan 11; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to above, 1955 Jan 2, Jan 9, 1955 Jan 12; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Waters, Edward C. to Shepard, 1955 Sep 1; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to Shepard, 1955 Sep 2, Sep 21; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Library of Congress (Keller, Alton) to Shepard, 1955 Oct 3; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to above, 1955 Oct 10; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1955 Oct 29; 2 typed letters (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to above, 1955 Nov 16; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Southern Music (Montalvo, Vilma) to Library, 1955 Nov 17; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1955 Nov 22; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Montalvo, 1955 Nov 25; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to Shepard, 1955 Nov 26; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - draft (Shepard) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1955 Dec 11; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Noss) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1956 Jan 17; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - autograph to Shepard, 1956 Feb 3; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1956 Feb 7; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Yale Music Library, verso draft Harmony Twichell Ives (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1956 Mar 29; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to above, 1956 Apr 4; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to Shepard, 1956 Nov 26; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Montalvo, 1956 Feb 9; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - John Kirkpatrick to Shepard, 1956 Feb 10; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Lakond, Wladimir to Shepard, 1956 Feb 14; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Strayer, Luther, 1956 Feb 14; typed letter signed (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Miller, Gardiner, H., 1956 Feb 14; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to Shepard, 1956 Feb 14; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Ruggles, Carl, 1956 Feb 14; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Babb, James, 1956 Feb 14; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Miller to Shepard, 1956 Feb 17; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Green, Ray to Shepard, 1956 Feb 21; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - from Harmony Twichell Ives for opening Ives Room, 1956 Feb 22; typed message (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - re opening, 1956 Feb 23; news clipping (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - opening concert, 1956 Feb 22; program (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - 1956 Feb 23, clippings (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Noss) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1956 Feb 24; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1956 Mar 29; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to above, 1956 Apr 4; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1961 Sep 25, 1962 May 25; 2 typed letters signed (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - (Shepard) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1962 May 2; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Tyler, George to John Kirkpatrick re estate of Harmony Twichell Ives, 1970 Apr 27; typed letter signed (copy) (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Yale College, Class of 1898 and others (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - 1896 Jun, printed entrance examination from scrapbook with jottings Charles Ives? (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - preliminary examination, printed (copy) (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - filled by Charles Ives, 1894 [?]; form (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Williams, Lewis) to "Quig", 1898 Oct 4; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Charles Ives to Henry [?], 1904 Mar 21; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - for reunion classbook filled by Charles Ives, 190[?]; printed form (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Wright, Henry B.) to Charles Ives, 1909 Nov 18; autograph postcard signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - ([?], Tom), 1919 [??]; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Van Beuren, Frederick T.), 1921 Mar 3; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Y'98 [?]), 1921 Mar 4; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (McLane, Thomas S.), 1921 Mar 9; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Crosby, Raymond M.), 1922 Oct 15; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - 25th reunion, 1923; announcement (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Clarke, Thomas B.), 1923 Mar 19; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Gillette, Curtenius), 1923 Mar 22; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - for reunion records filled by Charles Ives to Ripley, Julian, 1923 Oct 26; printed form (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Baldwin, Arthur D.), 1924 Sep 30; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Van Beuren), 1926 Jul 6, 1933 Oct 5, Nov 15; 3 typed letters signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Van Beuren), 1933 Nov 27; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Van Beuren), 1933 Nov 27; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Van Beuren), 193? Jan 28; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Fletcher, George), 1937 Apr 27; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Davis, Pierpont V.), 1937 Apr 29; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Fletcher), 1937 Jun 1; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Ripley), 1937 Jun 18, Sep 27; 2 typed postcards (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Richards, Alfred), 1939 Feb 26; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Turnbull, Robert), 1939 Apr 23; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - to University Club (Ripley) concert of Charles Ives by John Kirkpatrick, 193[?] May 17; printed invitation (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Yale College, Class of 1898 and others, printed dinner announcement for honoring Charles Ives signed by class of '98 (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Ripley), 1939 May 24; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Van Beuren), 1939 Jul 25, Aug 12; 2 typed letters signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Charles Ives to above, no date; draft (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Merrill, Charles E.), 1940 Jun 10; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Charles Ives to above, 1940 Jul 18; check (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Merrill), 1940 Jul 19; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Merrill), 1940 Jul 29; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Charles Ives to above, no date; draft (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Merrill), 1940 Aug 2; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Yale College, Class of 1898 and others, enc brochure (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - death of Merrill, 1942 Feb 10; printed announcement (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Ripley, Julien), 1943 Jun 20; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - 1948 Nov, excerpt from Yale Alumni Magazine (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Lockman, John), 1946 Apr 17; typed letter (copy) (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Richards, Priscilla for Alfred), 1946 May 1; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Ripley), 1948 Apr 6; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - 50th reunion, 1948 Jun 21; printed announcement (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Kennedy, Sidney R.), 1950 Apr 21; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Charles Ives to Ripley, no date; draft (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - (Ripley), 1956 Feb 12; autograph letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - no date, reunion announcement (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - The Year in American Music (Hurwitz, Lillian), 1948 Apr 2; typed letter signed (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Charles Ives to above, draft (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, III.C
    - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces (Box 37, Folder 1)
      All autograph unless otherwise indicated.
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, 2 typed (copy) pages on Psalm 67 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, 1 page numbered 3, perhaps of Postface of In The Night (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, page of corrections to a violin and piano sonata (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, typed page with corrections by Charles Ives about Central Park (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, page of jottings on Fourth Symphony, second movement (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, page of writing on First Orchestral Set (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, page of writing on First Piano Sonata (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, page by Harmony Twichell Ives on First Piano Sonata (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, draft by Charles Ives to Talmage on title page of Violin Sonata No. 4 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, folder Charles Ives scribble recto, Harmony Twichell Ives ? label "About the War Song March" enc of three jottings (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, emph: Musical Courier (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, 10 unidentified scraps (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, page on Third Violin Sonata, first movement [hand of Babitz or Dahl?] (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, typed (copy) listing movements for Quarter Tone Pieces (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, on music: poem on music, miscellaneous autograph memos, scraps, jottings; marginalia, on reviews, advertisements, and other writings; Charles Ives comments on envelopes and other items; several pages removed from scrapbooks. (Box 37, Folder 2)
        See also V/45/Miscellaneous autobiographical
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, non-music: similar materials of writings and memos (Box 37, Folder 3)
        See also V/45/12/Miscellaneous autobiographical
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, 31 pp lists of various kinds (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, 31 pp unidentified memos, scraps, writings (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous writings and jottings relating to individual pieces, miscellaneous insurance writings, memos, other insurance writings with Charles Ives marginalia, unidentified draft pages with corrections and additions. (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - 1955, 138 letters from libraries to Harmony Twichell Ives in thanks for 114 Songs (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Tax Records - Income Tax returns
      (given to Vivian Perlis by Watson Washburn in 1972)
      These are the personal tax files of Harmony and Charles Ives.
      Included are lists of deductions, charitable and otherwise, and all other correspondence relating to personal income tax.
      - 1913-1920 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - 1921-1923 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - 1924-1926 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - 1927-1929 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - 1930-1932 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - 1933-1934 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - 1935-1938 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - 1939-1944 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - 1946-1948 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - 1949-1950 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Documents
      - Documents, envelope in Harmony Twichell Ives hand with enc about "the old house" (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - no date, outer cover of passport (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - no date, wedding announcement of Edith to George Tyler (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Documents, birth record of Charles E. Ives (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - 1934 Aug 10, passenger list S.S. Pennland (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - 1894 Nov 14, autograph tribute to George E. Ives from the Savings Bank of Danbury, signed by John W. Bacon, President and Henry Ryder, Secretary (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Documents, will of Lyman D. Brewster (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - 1904 Jan 20, hand of Moss Ives (copy) (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - 1904 Jan 19, typed Codicil to the Last Will of Lyman D. Brewster signed by Lyman D. Brewster (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Documents, copies of correspondence and medical reports from Joslin Clinic (Box 39, Folder 1)
        See also III.B/34/14/Joslin Clinic
      - Documents, "Community Map of West Redding" (copy) (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Documents, miscellaneous items sent to Charles Ives, general, and items found in the correspondence with no marginalia: 18 brochures, clippings (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Documents, 10 miscellaneous items, personal; no marginalia (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Documents, miscellaneous relating to Harmony Twichell Ives with some notes in her hand: 4 poems, clippings (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Documents, 13 miscellaneous items, political; no marginalia (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Documents, 25 miscellaneous items, musical (Box 39, Folder 6)
- Scrapbooks, Series IV; 5 boxes
  There are eight scrapbooks: four large; four smaller in size. The larger scrapbooks were numbered by Ives. All follow a loose chronological order. For reasons of preservation, letters and other valuable items that could be removed without damage have been placed elsewhere in the Collection.
  - "Charles E. Ives Family Scrapbook", 1927-1936; Ives Scrapbook no. 1 (Box 40)
  - Music I, 1879-1935; Ives Scrapbook no. 2 (Box 40a)
  - Music II, Ives Scrapbook no. 3 (Box 41)
  - General Music, Ives Scrapbook no. 4 (Box 42)
  - Family and General, (small) (Box 43)
  - Music, (small) (Box 43)
  - Music, (small) (Box 44)
  - Business, (small) (Box 44)
- Diaries, Series V; 1 box
  The diaries and notebooks were numbered by John Kirkpatrick. Photographs in "Our Book" (Box 45/7/D7) have been copied and can be found also in the Photograph Collection of this register, Series VI. For the history and full description of the Diaries, See John Kirkpatrick Catalogue, preface. Transcriptions may be found in the John Kirkpatrick Papers, Box 87, Folder 799.
  - Moss Ives diary, 1885; John Kirkpatrick no. D1 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Charles Ives, 1886-1892; John Kirkpatrick no. D2 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Moss Ives account book, 1889 Jan 1-1891 Mar 23; John Kirkpatrick no. D3 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Charles Ives music datebook, 1889-1891; John Kirkpatrick no. D4 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Charles Ives programs of music Center Church, 1896-1897 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Harmony Twichell Ives diary, 1905-1907; John Kirkpatrick no. D6 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Charles Ives, Harmony Twichell Ives "Our Book", John Kirkpatrick no. D7 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Harmony Twichell Ives, Charles Ives diary, 1919-1920 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Edith Ives diary, 1924 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Harmony Twichell Ives, Charles Ives, Edith Ives trip to England, 1924 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Harmony Twichell Ives European diary, 1932-1933 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous autobiographical jottings as for a diary (Box 45, Folder 12)
    All transcribed by John Kirkpatrick. Perhaps meant to be part of Memos.
- Photographs, Series VI; 5 boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This collection includes most of the existing iconographic material relating to Charles Ives. For other collections, see the Scott Fanton Museum, the MONY Library, and private collectors Earl Gilmore and James Burk.
  In addition to the photographic materials given by Mrs. Ives to the Library along with the manuscripts and memorabilia in 1954, other items have been placed in this file by John Kirkpatrick and Vivian Perlis. Amelia Van Wyck, Ives's cousin, contributed family photographs and George Tyler, Ives's son-in-law, has been generous in allowing copies of photographs to be made from originals which are in the Ives house at West Redding.
  There are 237 items in the collection (and some miscellaneous materials). Each item has been given a number. Two negatives and a 5 x 7 glossy print have been made for each photograph and labeled with the corresponding number. The prints are placed in three albums and are to be used for viewing and for photographic orders. The original materials are in box 46 of the Ives Papers and may be seen on request.
  This register includes:
  Number of each item.